newzealandnow.govt.nz 2018-01-27

# About this site | New Zealand Now

Immigration New Zealand (INZ) is part of the Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment (MBIE), a New Zealand Government department.

MBIE’s primary role is to be a catalyst for a high-performing economy to ensure New Zealand’s lasting prosperity and wellbeing. The core information provided on this website is sourced by Immigration New Zealand from official government material, except where indicated otherwise.

## Copyright

Material featured on this site is subject to Crown copyright protection unless otherwise indicated. The Crown copyright protected material may be reproduced free of charge in any format or media without requiring specific permission. This is subject to the material being reproduced accurately and not being used in a derogatory manner or in a misleading context. Where the material is being published or issued to others, the source and copyright status must be acknowledged. The original source of the material is accessible by hyperlink at the location of reference to such material on this website

The permission to reproduce Crown copyright protected material does not extend to any material on this site that is identified as being the copyright of a third party. Authorisation to produce such material must be obtained from the copyright holders concerned. Please refer to the applicable licence for information about using and copying material that is subject to a 'creative commons' licence.

Images and videos contained within this site may be subject to have restrictions on their use, including being owned by third parties, and must not be used or reproduced without obtaining the permission of the copyright holder.

## Privacy policy

This website is provided by Immigration New Zealand, which is part of the Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment (MBIE).

The privacy notice applies to personal and other information collected on the New Zealand Now website.

Certain sections of the privacy notice (the “Data collection and purpose specification”, “Confidentiality/Security” and “Access to the personal data we may hold about you”) also apply where you have voluntarily provided personal information to a third party, via their website, and that information is then provided to us. (For example, where you have registered your personal details in order to request a copy of a publication.)

MBIE itself clarifies that it has no control over and is not responsible for the contents of any pages referenced or accessed from this server other than pages provided by the Ministry. Pages provided by the Ministry can be recognised by the URL name of the page containing "newzealandnow.govt.nz". Any hyperlinks to other Web sites imply neither responsibility for, nor approval of, the information contained in those other websites on the part of the Ministry.

If you find something that you think may be wrong, get in touch. We will pass your comments on to the agency concerned. You should always consider carefully whether the information you find through newzealandnow.govt.nz applies to you. If you are not sure, contact the government department providing the information, or get advice from someone you trust. Look for a page called "Contact Us" at the bottom of each page. This will provide you with contact details that you can use get in touch or please email [marketinginz@mbie.govt.nz](mailto:marketinginz@mbie.govt.nz). 

You can request a copy of the personal information we hold on the [Immigration New Zealand website](https://www.immigration.govt.nz/contact/request-information)

## Providing visitors with anonymous access

You can access our website home page and browse our site without having to disclose any personal data.

## Data collection and purpose specification

We do, however, collect some personal data that you may volunteer while using our site and its services. We generally do not collect or use personal data for any purpose other than to send out relevant immigration information, publications requested by you or to improve the relevance of our content.

If you have subscribed to the 'connect me with jobs from New Zealand employers through LinkedIn' checkbox on the registration form, you have agreed for your first name, last name, email address, and New Zealand Now ID being shared with LinkedIn for matching purposes. You may unsubscribe from this service by clicking the 'unsubscribe' button at the bottom of any emails from New Zealand Now. Please allow 24 hours for this to come into effect. 

If you are registered with New Zealand Now and travel to New Zealand, we will use your information to email you on arrival. 

As with all personal information you provide to any New Zealand organisation, your privacy is protected by law. We will never release your details to third parties for commercial use without your prior permission. 

Any personal information we hold will not be used by us for any purpose other than the one you provided it for, or disclosed to any other person in a form that will identify you except where you have consented to such disclosure, or where such use or disclosure is required or otherwise permitted by the Privacy Act 1993, or otherwise required or permitted by law. 

## Automatic collection of information

We use site statistics to improve the information on this site and create relevant content.

This information includes:

  * users' IP addresses
  * users' search terms
  * pages accessed on the site
  * links that are clicked on
  * date and time of site visits
  * previous visited site
  * users' operating systems
  * browsers used when accessing the site.

This information is viewable by site administrators and certain other department staff. It may also be shared with other government agencies.

Google may also collect some or all of this information when javascript is turned on in your Internet browser. This is due to the site using a portion of the Google public index for its search functionality. Google’s use of such information is addressed in its Privacy Policy.

## Cookies

This Site generates both persistent and temporary cookies (files that a website transfers to your computer).

Some cookies may collect personal information you may decide to disclose by providing identifying information within the search terms you enter into the Site or when completing one of the online registration forms.

The Site generates temporary cookies to monitor site usage and to maintain site presentation for those who wish to use the Site’s high contrast view. These particular cookies are named “__utmc” and “default_stylesheet”. They do not store any personal information and are deleted immediately when you close your browser.

If you prefer not to use cookies, you can still use the Site. To find out how to disable cookies, check the Help instructions in your web browser.

## Remarketing

This site utilises Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online. It allows third-party vendors, including Google, to show Immigration New Zealand's ads on sites across the Internet. This is done by this site and third-party vendors, including Google, using first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone's past visits to this website.

## Confidentiality/Security

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the personal data that we have under our control from:

  * Unauthorised access
  * Improper use or disclosure
  * Unauthorised modification
  * Unlawful destruction or accidental loss

All our employees and data processors, who have access to, or associated with the processing of personal data, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our online visitors’ personal data.

Cookies are in use on this website. They pick up anonymous data for the purpose of gathering statistics only.

MBIE websites have security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control. In order to maintain the cyber security of MBIE systems and information, MBIE systems are subject to ongoing monitoring (including activity logging), analysis and auditing.

We may use information about your use of our websites and other IT systems to prevent unauthorised access or attacks on these systems or to resolve such events. We may use this information even if you are not involved in such activity. MBIE may utilise services from one or more 3rd party suppliers to monitor or maintain the cyber security of its systems and information. These 3rd party suppliers will have access to monitoring and logging information as well as information processed on MBIE websites and other IT systems.

## Access to the personal data we may hold about you

You have the right to access and to request correction of any of your personal information provided to us in connection with your use of this Site. If you would like to see the personal information relating to you that we have stored, or to request correction of such personal information, or if you have any concerns regarding your privacy, please contact us at the address below. We may require proof of your identity before being able to provide you with any personal information.

For such an enquiry, please email [marketinginz@mbie.govt.nz](mailto:marketinginz@mbie.govt.nz).

If you are not satisfied with our response to any privacy-related concern you may have, you can contact the Privacy Commissioner:  
     Office of the Privacy Commissioner  
     PO Box 10-094  
     Wellington, New Zealand  
     Phone: +64-4-474 7590  
     Enquiries Line (from Auckland): 302 8655  
     Enquiries Line (from outside Auckland): 0800 803 909  
     Fax: +64-4-474 7595  
     Email: [enquires@privacy.org.nz](mailto:enquires@privacy.org.nz)  

## Disclaimer

This is an official government website designed to provide general information and resources. The Ministry does not accept any responsibility or liability to you, whether in contract, equity or tort, or under any other legal principle, for any direct or indirect losses or damage of any kind arising from use of this site. This includes any action taken as a result of reading, or a reliance placed on the Department as a result of having read, any part or all of, the information on this site.

Without limiting the above, you are advised that:

  * The information provided is of a general nature only, and is not intended to address specific circumstances of any particular individual or entity.
  * MBIE/Immigration New Zealand may change, add to, delete from, or otherwise amend the content of this site without notice.
  * MBIE/Immigration New Zealand makes no warranties, guaranties or undertakings as to results that may be obtained from information contained on this web site. Information provided is not professional or legal advice. Specific advice should be sought from qualified professionals prior to relying on any information received at this site.
  * The information provided is not in substitution or in any way an alteration to the laws of New Zealand or any other official guidelines or requirements.

## Linked websites

Hypertext links to other web locations are for the convenience of users and do not constitute any endorsement by MBIE. The Ministry is not responsible for the contents or reliability of the linked websites and does not necessarily endorse the views expressed within them. We cannot guarantee that these links will work and we have no control over availability of linked pages.

## Content that may be inaccessible

Whilst we endeavour to make the content of this site accessible to all users, users who cannot access documents but wish to obtain access to the document, may contact us at [marketinginz@mbie.govt.nz](mailto:marketinginz@mbie.govt.nz). Users may also find information and tips to assist them on our accessibility page.
